Artem Pakhomov

Senior PHP Developer from Lviv, Ukraine

Phone: +380 (50) 027-93-00
Email: setnemo@gmail.com
Github: https://github.com/setnemo

Other Social Media: @setnemo



I have been working in the web industry for the past seven years. I'm writing a code according to SOLID, KISS, YAGNI, DRY. I'm publishing all my pet projects on Github as I adore open source. I'm a backend developer, and I fancy creating telegram bots. I began studying to play piano during the lockdown. This CV was created on PHP with GitHub Actions as I can't live without automation. I am married, have 2 kids and 3 cats. I like to spend time with my family, read books, watch TV series.

Technologies

PHP: OOP, SOLID, REST, TDD, PHPDoc, PSR, MVC, Composer, Laravel

DB and Brokers: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, RabbitMQ

Tests: PHPUnit, Codeception

Git: understand rebase, reflog, squash, cherry-pick, soft/hard reset, etc

Unix: used ArchLinux, Debian, Mint, Ubuntu, macOS, vim, grep, sed, awk, ssh, etc

Containers: docker, k8s

Dev environment: nginx/docker, Postman, PHPStorm, xDebug, Makefile

Experience

Senior PHP Developer at Social Media (NDA) Lviv, Ukraine - 04/2022 - Present

Project details are prohibited by non-disclosure agreement

Lead PHP Developer at Blockster Kyiv, Ukraine - 04/2021 - 03/2022 ~1 year

- I was implemented the way which was provided migration from old legacy code (white label) to the modern application (Laravel)
- I was implemented a metrics (raw data to Postgres, aggregated to Prometheus) and an experiment (for A/B testing on backend) system, which provides more understanding about user experience with our product
- I was mentored the backend developers team (~5 backend) and helped other teams with processes, cross-team developing, sharing knowledge
- I was provided changes for processes: move gitlab issues to Jira (create automation), create workflows for all colleagues(design/development/qa), taught colleagues use it.
- I was created some automation for a lot of things, which made more clearly and useful decomposition/developing/testing/duty flow

PHP Developer at airSlate Inc Kyiv, Ukraine - 05/2019 - 04/2021 ~2 years

- I wrote code with tests and documentation, made code review
- I deployed on dev/rc for testing, deployed releases on production
- I configured alert rules and checking the cause of alerts, working with metrics (tech and business)

PHP Developer at Wallet Factory Kyiv, Ukraine - 01/2019 - 05/2019 ~6 months

- Back-end development for a Fin-tech mobile application.
- PHP 7+, OpenSSL, payments API integrations
- API integrations for sales/discounting etc

PHP Developer at MakeTop Kyiv, Ukraine - 05/2015 - 12/2018 ~3,5 years

- I wrote implementation for search engine optimization
- I was working with popular CMS and self-hosted websites.

Education

Software Architect UNIT Factory, Kyiv - 09/2017 - 11/2018

I was one of 5 students with the best marks in UNIT Factory (course 2017), I completed the 3-year program (Ecole 42, France) in 1 year. UNIT Factory StudHub. Volunteering in Exam. Event organization. Meet-up organization.

Pet projects

Repeat Word Bot https://t.me/RepeatWordBot

- Telegram bo which help you revise new English words and learn pronunciation
- PHP, Doctrine, MySQL, Redis, Codeception, Docker, GitHub Actions

Currencies in UA Bot https://t.me/CurrencyUA bot

- Currency conversion (inline) for Ukraine
- PHP, MySQL, Redis, Api integrations, Docker

Asterios RB bot https://github.com/setnemo/asterios-bot

- Bot that helps more than 2000 players from Asterios Lineage II Server
- PHP, MySQL, Redis, Codeception, Docker, Github Actions

Begone github.com/setnemo/bygone

- Archive your old repositories to one repo (git history included) with Github Actions
- · bash, git, Github Actions

Publications

There, Tsar Kashchei wasted away over gold; or how to save all old repositories into one including git history (Russian)

https://habr.com/ru/post/570404/

Archive your old repositories to one repo (git history included) with Github Actions. The article was removed by myself after russia started to missiles at Ukraine

Introduction to Metrics for PHP Developer (Russian)

https://habr.com/ru/post/544582/

The purpose of the article is to acquaint the reader with the principles of working with metrics in php. A ready-made mini-project in docker has been prepared for the article. The article was removed by myself after russia started to missiles at Ukraine

Refactoring a pet project: dockerization, metrics, tests (Russian)

https://habr.com/ru/post/542978/

The story of how I refactored one of my telegram bots, which from a makeshift turned into a service with more than 1000 users in a very narrow and specific audience. The article was removed by myself after russia started to missiles at Ukraine

Languages

English - Professional proficiency, (fluent intermediate)

Russian - Native or bilingual proficiency

Ukrainian - Full professional proficiency

Volunteer experience

SuperGrandchildren at Happy Lunch

CO "Lifelover" happyold.com.ua

Kyiv, Ukraine - 05/2019 - 03/2020